Ethan Mylett

440.523.1811 • Rocky River, OH • ethan.mylett@yahoo.com • LinkedIn

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Recent college graduate with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Engineering. Focused on data systems and analytics with experience in data structures, algorithms, data science, cloud technologies, machine learning, and mathematics. Proficiency in Java, JavaScript, Python, AWS, C, C#, C++, Tensorflow, Pytorch, SQL, and Microsoft Suite.

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University | Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Engineering

2020 - 2024

- Specialization in Database Systems & Data Analytics
- Magna Cum Laude, GPA 3.745

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Spotify Playlist Curator:

Technologies - Javascript, Python, SQL, ElasticSearch, React, Node.Js, React-Three-Fiber, Docker, Agile Development

• Built a Spotify playlist generator with Spotify API and ElasticSearch integration to create personalized playlists from a 100,000+ song database. Users' favorite artists and genres are used to produce a dynamic playlist of a specified length. Features 3D visualizations of the playlist's parameters using React-Three-Fiber. Developed in collaboration with a team of 5 talented teammates.

NFL Spread Prediction App:

Technologies - Pytorch, React, Flask, Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit Learn

• Developed an NFL game spread prediction web app using PyTorch, React, and Flask. Trained a neural network on data from 10,000+ games, each with 50+ features from 1979 onward, achieving >90% test accuracy. This app allows users to input game stats to receive data driven betting spread predictions.

Gesture Recognition for Input Control:

Technologies - TensorFlow, MediaPipe, Python

• Created a gesture-based mouse control system using TensorFlow and MediaPipe in Python. Leveraged an innovative pre-trained model to identify 21 hand key points and recognize gestures with 97.5% accuracy. Integrated with a webcam, this system was prototyped to let users control mouse movement and clicks in real-time using only hand gestures.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VIP Valet | Cleveland, OH

April 2023 - August 2023

Valet Attendant

Coordinated with the valet team to manage the flow of incoming and outgoing vehicles, ensuring a flexible and organized process during rushes. Effectively communicated with customers, answered questions, provided information on services, and offered assistance when needed, contributing to a high level of customer satisfaction.

Market | Rocky River, OH

March 2019 - August 2022

Barback.

Collaborated with the bar team to manage inventory, track usage, and communicate restocking needs, minimizing downtime and improving operational efficiency. Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills by efficiently identifying and resolving everyday logistical challenges such as sudden increases in customer demand and unexpected shortages.

Mitchell's Ice Cream | Rocky River, OH

May 2016 - December 2018

Team Leader

Promoted to Team Leader in two months. Led a team of 4–8 members to ensure efficient operation and customer satisfaction on shifts with thousands of customers. Acted as shift manager, facilitating restocks of over 50 items.

ACTIVITIES

- Ohio State University Golf Club, 2022–2024, Two-time National Collegiate Club Golf Association Competitor
- American Legion Buckeye Boys State Participant, 2018